Suraya Clemens

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

www.suraya.xyz surayaclemens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/suraya-clemens github.com/surayaclemens

PROFILE

I see web development as a tool to combine my love of creating cool things with my responsibility to work towards a more equitable future, and seek engagements that prioritize accessibility & inclusivity along with innovation.

Outside my work in the tech sector, my background in linguistics provided me with practical experience in both logical and humanist thinking, and my academic accomplishments demonstrate that I execute top quality work.

Complementing these hard skills is my extensive experience in customer service, which cultivated my ability to identify and meet interpersonal needs, and form lasting positive relationships.

My colleagues know me as an excellent communicator, thorough problem solver, initiative-taker, and big fan of jokes.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, Express, Node, Firebase, SQL, DOM APIs, Web APIs, User Auth, OAuth, Heroku, GCP, Docker, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Agile Methodology

EXPERIENCE

Comprehensive list on LinkedIn

Software Engineer - Full-stack Web Developer | Cedulify

AUG 2022 - Present, REMOTE/MONTREAL, QC

- Front-end: responsible for all UI and front-end functionality, implementation of accessibility requirements, responsive design adaptation (Angular, TypeScript, SCSS, and third party libraries)
- Back-end: endpoints for calls to our database and web APIs, CRUD operations, database structuring to optimize internationalization, assisted in dev ops
- Product: close collaboration with design team and CEO on user flows, interface, feature priorities
- **Project management**: restructured company's Jira for stronger efficiency with Agile methodology, implemented various systems to manage dev team's work re: sprints, version releases, etc.
- Within 6 months: shipped product from ideation to production using entirely new stack, implemented internationalization & localization for a bilingual app, created UX flows and UI components that were approved and implemented

Research Assistant | Syrians Learning English for Employment in Canada (SLEEC), University of Victoria

SEP 2021 - APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

- Planned and conducted academic study within SLEEC pilot program to inform the language-learning experience of refugees and newcomers to Canada
- Executed through survey composition, literature review, participant interviews, qualitative content analysis, synthesis of findings + graphic design for presentation, public speaking

Web Designer | Van Brothers Forming Ltd.

DEC 2020 - MAR 2021, REMOTE/VANCOUVER, BC

- Designed and produced a re-branded marketing site to meet industry standards and attract bigger clients
- Exceeded stakeholder goals by refining site architecture, improving UX and modernizing UI

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

JUL 2022, VANCOUVER, CA

University of Victoria | Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

APR 2022, VICTORIA, CA

GPA 4.0, Undergraduate Research Award, President's Scholarship

PROJECTS

- Ayajuthem Tetris: Gamified learning for Indigenous language revitalization (React, JS, SCSS, Node, SQL)
- Alatúlie: English to Elvish translator (React, JS, SCSS, Node)